Well, good morning.
I'm Steve Ross,
chairman
of the Miami Dolphins.
I'm very excited to be here today
as we really what I hope starts a new
beginning.
I know many of you were all frustrated
over the last few years
with the performance of the team,
but I got to tell you I am equally
frustrated.
And therefore,
you know,
when I when I first bought the team,
I said certain things that I would do
and were and what were Excuse me.
[clears throat] And what were important
to me.
One was
establishing a winning football team
that played for Super Bowls on a
continual basis. The second
was to really make this team and this
county
much better, to bring it together, and
have an obligation to really be
supportive of the county, and really be
the best-in-class football organization.
I think we've accomplished two of those
things.
But the frustration and probably what
everybody looks to in the Miami Dolphins
is about winning football.
That's the way I live. That's the way I
believe in, and I believe that's the
only way you do business. There's only
room in one place. It's at the top.
So, the rest of it is very crowded.
And so, the frustrations
I know that you've all had reading the
newspapers, which I don't read anymore
because it just emphasizes to me the
frustration that I have. So, I really
look to this to really be a new
beginning.
And we've done
>> [clears throat]
>> And getting ready for that, you know,
you could see what was happening
uh during the season. Um we started
early and really so that we could be
very thorough in our search in trying to
find the right people to lead this
organization.
And I'd like to first of all thank the
people that really worked, you know,
tirelessly and and
talking, thinking, working together.
I'd like to thank
>> [clears throat]
>> It was really headed up with uh Tom
Garfinkel and Danny Saliman,
Brandon Shore,
Dan Marino,
and Troy Aikman.
And we were able to really use the
knowledge that they all had in really
trying to find the best leadership for
this team going forward.
And
>> [clears throat]
>> we really were were very thorough um
knowing what we were going about. And
you know, when you when you really look
and think about people, you want to get
people who are winners. People who came
from winning organizations, so they know
what winning is. You know, it was like I
guess probably the greatest remark is
that
winning is important or winning isn't
the
only thing, the Vince Lombardi line,
it's the only thing. And so, having that
kind of ideas, because that's what these
people really believe in, really led us
on our search. We were very very
thorough um
in in
um
re- reviewing who was available,
what people thought of them, what their
backgrounds were, and um I think, you
know, by doing that, we were really in a
position to really be able to pick the
coach that we thought was would be the
best. But we first started with the
general manager, which we had some time.
And one person clearly stood out. I
mean, the experience he
he had and having really been part of
winning organizations,
Super Bowls,
um and but his enthusiasm for the game
and his knowledge of the game, and the
knowledge of how the league works, and
what it takes to create a winner, stood
out far and above anybody we spoke to. I
know
uh the first conversation we could have
with him was via Zoom, and then 10 about
minutes into it, I just said, "Hey,
this is our guy."
And I'm very very thrilled to really,
you know, welcome
John Eric Sullivan
uh as our general manager.
And then we had to go out and find a
of the coach, you know, and I knew I
thought maybe he was really be partial
to, you know, uh
the Green Bay Packers, but we were
really totally thorough, and he was
totally objective. And and after
interviewing, talking to people, there
were all real really great candidates. I
think the enthusiasm, the knowledge, the
background, um
it it's um
um
Jeff
stood out amongst them all. So, we were
really fortunate that he was available.
We made our decision early. As you know,
there were many openings this year,
probably more than ever before,
and I'm very happy to be standing today
knowing we got who we wanted, and that
the rest of the teams are still looking.
So, we are now preparing, really getting
ready immediately to really fulfill the
ideas of what we all want to see
is a new generation of winning football
games and being very very competitive.
Um so, with that, I'd like to
introduce
John Eric.
What?
You want me to sit here?
I'd rather you stand up.
Stand up? I had no idea I had to be
sure.
I think you know what she means.
I mean, I know she's the boss today,
though, so I apologize.
Thank you.
You're the baby.
What?
The boss is calling you.
I think she [laughter] wants you to go
over there.
Good job. You want me to stand here?
Or do you want me to stand there? Oh,
I'm done.
All right.
>> [snorts]
>> Good morning to everyone. Appreciate
everybody being here. I think before I
even get started,
the most important thing is for me to
express gratitude, and it starts with
the Ross family, uh especially Stephen.
Um
You have bestowed upon me an opportunity
of a lifetime. Uh I could I will be
forever grateful.
The magnitude and responsibility
of what lies before me in this role does
not fall short on me.
Um I will go to work every day and work
tirelessly along with the other great
people in the building, the leadership
committee, to bring you the winner that
you deserve.
To the search committee, Danny, Tom,
Brandon,
Troy, uh your wisdom, your guidance,
your communication throughout the
process
was invaluable to me and this
organization. Um I can't thank you
enough. Uh [snorts] it was a long road,
but it was a very uh productive and
fruitful road, and I think we uh we
ended up where we needed to be. So,
thank you.
Saying that, it was a nice look under
the hood for me
in terms of the collaboration and the
work ethic and the communication that
will allow us to do a lot of really
excellent things together down the road.
To the Packers organization,
I said I wouldn't do this.
I was very very very lucky to land where
I landed 22 years ago.
Um
very lucky to be mentored by some of the
best in the business, phenomenal people
that happened to also be excellent with
what they did in their profession.
I was very fortunate to be entrenched in
a process, a proven process that brought
30 years of sustained success to that
place, and that others have left and
gone on to have success around the
National Football League with. John
Schneider, John Dorsey, Reggie McKenzie.
If you do your homework, you see what
this process will bring to the table
when the opportunity presents itself to
implement it.
>> [snorts]
>> I have to start with Mark Hatley. He's
the one that hired me, God rest his
soul. We didn't have a chance to work
together long, but uh he brought me
through the door. Obviously, I'm not
standing here today without him.
Ted Thompson.
Ted Thompson, in my opinion, is one of
the best ever do it. He was the guy that
was seen, not heard. He trusted the
process, and more importantly, he
trusted the process
through times of adversity. He never
wavered. We will implement that here,
that same thought process, that same
conviction with how we move and work
every day.
The thing that I will take away from
him, mo- most importantly, is beyond
anything, he always always did what is
best for the team.
Um I will not stand up here and make a
whole lot of promises today, but the one
thing I will tell you, and I think it's
vitally important for everybody to know,
especially the players that are here,
every decision that falls in within my
line of responsibility
will be what's for the Miami Dolphins,
unequivocally.
It will never be about
personal relationships or personal
agendas. It'll be what's best for this
place and the greater good.
>> [snorts]
>> Brian Gutekunst Brian Gutekunst was
probably
uh
who had the most impact on me because of
how our careers fell. I was always kind
of chasing Brian. He was a Southeast
scout then I was a Southeast scout then
he was the college director then I was
the college director and so on and so
forth.
Having said that he was a tremendous
sounding board for me all the way
through.
Um his belief and faith in me I can
never repay him for and I'm grateful for
the relationship. He's one of the best
in the business.
The thing that he showed me and taught
me is preparation preparation
preparation.
Player acquisition is a
it's an everyday 365-day year job. Uh it
does not stop and you have to be
prepared and ready to strike when the
opportunity presents itself. We will
move with responsible aggression here.
Uh we will utilize every avenue of
player acquisition to bolster this
roster and uh working with him and
alongside of him has showed me how to do
that at a high level and I think that
will benefit this place as we move
forward.
Mark Murphy and Ed Policy uh the two
presidents in my time there
I cannot thank you enough for the
support and the guidance
and uh
I'm just a very appreciative for the
longevity that you allowed me to have
within the organization.
To my greatest mentor uh my father
My dad's a 30-year NFL coach or close to
it. Longtime college coach before that.
He allowed me to see the game uh at a
very high level at a very young age
which gave me pedigree uh that has got
me to where I am today.
Uh no shot I'm standing here without him
uh and I
words will never do it justice but thank
you.
And then obviously my family. This is
impossible without you.
I'm going to get beat up in the media
for even starting like this guy couldn't
keep it together.
>> [snorts]
>> Being a dad to you Samantha you CC you
Mia and then a husband to you Jen
is uh the greatest honor of my life.
Regardless whatever we accomplish in
this profession
nothing ever trumps that so just know
that.
>> [snorts]
>> In my short time here with ownership and
the leadership
I can sense
a burning desire to win
and do things the right way.
I said it before and I'll say it again.
Um I don't take it lightly that I've
been put in this position and every day
that I walk through those doors
I along with the other great people in
this building will make sure that we do
everything possible to bring you and
your family Stephen the winner that you
deserve.
>> [snorts]
>> The goal is simple. It's a standard of
excellence. We're chasing championships.
It's as simple as that.
This is a tough business.
It is not a complicated business in my
opinion.
And the things that we do day in and day
out
the little things will get us where we
want to go.
>> [snorts]
>> Together we will implement a proven
process. We'll build something special
but we'll build something that is
sustainable over time.
>> [snorts]
>> It's not going to be an easy road
but I think the journey is well worth
going on
and we will do it together and we will
achieve together and when we get to the
end of this thing and we hoist that
trophy
we'll realize that we
started at the bottom. We fought our way
to the top and it'll be one of the more
special moments of all of our lives. I
have no doubt that we will get there.
>> [snorts]
>> The pillars
we will be a draft and develop
philosophy. I've already spoken on that
in in previous interviews.
Um but we will draft develop and retain
our own.
There are things that come with that.
Number one is culture.
When you raise your own
people are vested. They're bought in.
There's a financial component to it with
rookie contracts that keeps you in a
healthy cap situation.
Um
but the most important thing is is the
culture piece of it.
>> [snorts]
>> Free agency we will be very intentional
and deliberate how we move about that.
We will definitely utilize it when we
get into a healthy cap situation and we
can
but we'll be disciplined. We'll be
intentional and we will chase
difference makers that add value to the
field immediately but also add value to
our locker room in terms of the kind of
culture that we want to build.
>> [snorts]
>> It's my job to turn over every rock
within the player acquisition
game if you will.
We will utilize every avenue and the
most important thing that I want
everybody to take away today is we will
bring in the right kind of I've said
many a times Miami is a very attractive
place to come and play football. It's an
attractive place to work.
But if you don't infuse this locker room
with the right kind of people
it can be a distraction in a hurry.
That is our job as a personnel staff to
give coach Halfley
the kind of guys that
want to chase championships that are
selfless that are mentally and
physically tough who have a burning
desire to be the best football players
that they can be.
>> [snorts]
>> Jeff Halfley
I can tell you today you've got a
phenomenal human being who is an
excellent football coach. This process
was thorough.
We spoke with a lot of very very
talented coaches
who brought a lot to the table.
And it was a great process because in
speaking with all of them it just
confirmed my conviction
on that this was the right guy. I got to
watch him work for two years.
Jeff is a friend of mine. We've become
friendly over the last two years but
understand this hire was based on
professional respect.
I watched him day in and day out connect
with players.
I watched his ability to teach. I've
watched his ability to inspire
and I've watched the intellect in the
organization
and how people coaches and players
around the building buy into him.
He will bring discipline and
accountability not only to his players
but to his coaching staff. Coaches will
have to teach. That is vitally
important. We're aligned in terms of
player development. I told you we're
going to draft we're going to develop
we're going to retain our our own but
that only works if you're aligned within
the player development part of things.
We are.
His emotional maturity his ability to
get through the bad times and keep
people on the ship when everybody else
wants to jump is something that stood
out to me.
And he is a master of the game.
Obviously defense is his trade but he's
got a a deep knowledge of special teams
and offense.
And I think more importantly the
toughness and the kind of attitude and
competitive atmosphere that he will
bring to this football team will speak
for itself as we move down the road.
Again I'm not here to make predictions.
That's not my job but we're going to set
a standard and a way of doing things
early on and as we move down the road I
have no doubt that will bring us to
where we want to go in terms of wins and
losses.
The culture of competition hard work
resilience and love
for each other
will bounce off the walls of this place
day in and day out to where you can't
deny what we're about. I thank you for
your time. I'm excited for this journey.
Let's go.
>> [applause]
>> It's nice when I don't have to adjust
the microphone too much cuz we're very
similar in size. It was that way in
Green Bay too with Matt so thank you
Sully.
Uh thank you Mr. Ross and and I'll get
to the thank yous as we get going. I
kind of want to
talk a little bit before that cuz I'll
probably get emotional but
I got to tell you you you kind of saw
the passion and how he got emotional and
how he cares and that's who he is and
and this place is really lucky to have
Sully as the GM and he's a huge part of
why I wanted to come here.
I'm not one to write things down. I'm
not one to to sit up here with a a
detailed plan on what I'm going to say.
I think for those that are going to
listen to me and ask questions what you
see with me is what you get. It's going
to come from the heart. It's going to be
honest and it's how I'm going to feel.
Um
I am truly humbled to stand here and be
the head coach of the Miami Dolphins and
I take a lot of pride and responsibility
in that. And over the last really 48
hours
I've had a lot of time to reflect on
that and on my journey and really where
I came from and how I got here.
And the biggest thing that kept hitting
me was people.
It's the players
it's the coaches
and it's the families. And as I really
go through it
it's all those lessons that I learned
in all the places that I've been. I've
had a little bit different journey. I
started off coaching Division III
football worked my way up went to the
NFL went back to college football became
a head coach went back to the NFL
coordinated and now I'm here but here's
what I learned.
I started coaching Division III football
where I lined fields and cleaned helmets
and did laundry and I loved it.
And what I learned was there's no job
too small.
And that's what you're going to get from
me every single day cuz I learned how to
work hard, like really hard.
And there's no replacement for that and
there won't be here.
And as I continue to move up, I learned
a lot from a lot of coaches.
I learned how to tell people the truth.
I learned how to tell players the truth
even if it wasn't they wanted to hear.
I learned that it's it's okay to tell a
player you love them
and to pour everything you can into them
because they're going to give it right
back to you.
I learned how to be at my best when
things get hard. And I learned that when
things are good, that's when I got to
put my thumb on them.
I learned what it's like to hold people
to an extreme level of accountability. I
learned what toughness is about and I
learned how to grind.
From Hall of Fame players I learned that
you got you can't be afraid to coach
guys. Every good player wants to be told
what to do and how hard to do it and you
can't back down cuz they all want to get
better.
I learned about alignment.
And that you have to have people's backs
and you have to come together, which is
a huge reason why I'm here today with
this guy right here.
I learned how to win and unfortunately
I've taken some losses.
But what I've learned I'm going to get
back up every single time and so were
those people that are around me every
single day.
And in doing that
I've kind of had the core beliefs, which
we're going to instill in this football
team
into the players and into this
organization.
And the first one is trust.
And a lot of people use that word
lightly, I don't. And I think right now
in the world we live in, a lot of people
are slow to trust. It might be you. It
might be the players and that's all
right cuz I'm going to earn it.
Because actions speak louder than words.
I'm not going to be able to I'm not
going to be one to sit here and talk a
lot but I'm going to follow up with what
I say I'm going to do. And so are our
team.
The next thing that I believe in is
belief.
And I think this is really powerful
because it's a hard world right now
where people read stuff, they see stuff
and you'd be surprised on how much
insecurity there is with players, with
coaches, with everybody.
And I'm going to let those players know
that I believe in them.
And in turn what you're going to see,
you're going to see a group of guys that
believe in themselves.
And that becomes powerful because when
they start to believe in themselves and
our team starts to connect with each
other, then look out.
Because you get that connection and then
we want to talk about accountability,
then we have accountability and
accountability's love. And it's an
extreme level of accountability. And
when we build a standard and it starts
to become real, the player will start to
hold themselves accountable. But that's
going to start with me.
And the final thing that I'm going to
talk to them about every single day is
toughness.
That's physically, that's mentally
that's everything that we do and it's a
toughness that thrives on competition.
And it's a toughness that reflects the
people and the spirit of the city of
Miami.
And that's what I'm most excited about.
And as we piece this thing together,
it's going to be it's going to take time
and there's going to be a lot of hard
work
but then it's going to be built the
right way like the foundation that was
laid for me when I was coaching Division
III football and I learned how to do
things the right way.
And that's how we're going to do it here
with a staff that's going to buy in and
with a group of men or that are getting
that are going to give everything that
they got.
And I can look you guys in the eye and
tell you I cannot wait to get started.
And now really to my thank you's to Mr.
Ross and your family, thank you for
believing in me.
I do not take that lightly and I will do
everything I can for you and your
family.
To everybody in this group from Sully
to Brandon, to Troy, to Dan, to Danny,
to Tom
thank you guys for believing in me in
this process. You guys put me through
multiple interviews. We spent time
talking to each other. We had multiple
hard conversations on phone calls but it
was always the communication. And it was
awesome.
And I appreciate it.
I want to thank all the coaches that
I've ever been around from WPI to Boston
College to every NFL team and I want to
thank the players
because I wouldn't be here without those
players.
I learned more from players than I've
learned from coaches and I hope they
feel that way with me cuz the thing that
I got into this for was changing lives
and there's so many of those players
that changed my life, too.
I want to thank Matt LaFleur and the
Green Bay Packers. The last 2 years have
been two of the best in my life.
Uh he's a great football coach, he's a
great friend and he's going to get have
continued great success. I also want to
thank those players there. In 2 years we
got real close. I mean really close. The
love, the connection, the support. It
was hard to say goodbye to those guys
but the phone calls and the texts you
guys meant everything to me. I love you.
I wish you the best other than when we
come to Lambeau next year.
I want to thank my family and this will
be
>> [snorts]
>> This is why I saved it for the end.
Hope and Leah
Hope's laughing now so that's good. Leah
I thank you guys and I thank Gina.
And I can tell you this about Gina.
Gina's not into this so she can walk
around tell people that she's married to
the head coach of the Dolphins. She
doesn't care.
All she cares about is us, how I'm
feeling, supporting me
and doing everything she can for those
kids.
I'm lucky today, too
cuz I got my mom
my sister, brother
>> [snorts]
>> here today.
Flying here to be with me
means everything
and I thank them for that.
And for my real coach, my dad
my first coach
who toughened me up
and was there for me.
I appreciate family more than you guys
have any and like I told you guys, I'm
going to I'm going to wear it on my
sleeve at times. I'm going to be
passionate. I'm going to tell you how I
feel and you're going to get everything
I have into this city, to the fans.
This is a story organization, one of the
best in all sports and you deserve a
winner.
You guys deserve a winner.
And I am going to do everything in my
power
to bring you guys that.
I am so proud to be here
and I cannot wait to get started. Thank
you.
>> [applause]
[snorts]
>> Hi, Hal Habib with the Palm Beach Post.
First I'd like to welcome both of you to
South Florida.
Thank you. [clears throat]
>> Um
I'd like to ask you when you were
talking with Stephen Ross over your two
roles um how did he lay out his
expectations, his vision for what you
would accomplish? Obviously I'm sure he
mentioned winning many, many times but
how did he put it to you? Was there any
kind of timetable that he expressed to
you? Was there any recognition of the
constraints you have with the salary
cap? What can you tell us about that?
I'll take that. You can start it. Sure.
So so what I would say to you right from
the jump and in my communications with
Stephen Ross was the like I said, the
desire to win.
Um but he he made it very clear. I mean
quite frankly his words to me were if
you don't get this done
you will never be able to say it was cuz
you didn't have the resources.
Which tells me everything I need to
know.
Um
I think we all know that every place is
not like that. Uh I come from a place
the last 22 years
it's all about winning. Every decision
we make is about winning. And I could
feel that from Stephen and Danny
[clears throat]
and Tom and everybody that was involved
in the process
from the jump. And so yes, there were
some more specific things that were
talked about but at the end of the day
the burning desire to win and his
ability to articulate how important it
was and what he was willing to do to get
there uh spoke volumes to me. I I to be
perfectly honest with you, of course I
wanted to be a general manager in the
National Football League but I wasn't
leaving to go just anywhere.
The place that I worked at afforded me
that flexibility.
This was very attractive to me because
of Stephen, his desire to win and the
things he's willing to do to get us
there.
Good answer.
Hi, uh Tim Reynolds with the AP. To echo
Hal and I'm sure everyone else, welcome
to South Florida. Um Jeff, I wanted to
ask you you you talked about your
journey and the D3 start.
Uh
how
different I guess are you or what what
what do you still take from Siena and Ed
Zullo and Bob Ford and
surely you didn't envision this but I
guess how much of that guy is still
within you? Yeah.
>> What you took from those those times?
One,
um thank you for bringing them up. I
mean I talked to Ed Zullo probably he
texts me before almost every game and
that that's the head coach who was at
WPI. And then Bob Ford is one of the
winningest coaches in all football. He
took Albany from Division III to II to
I-AA all the way to I
and he's one of the best to ever do it.
I learned everything from those guys.
It's what I just talked about. It laid
my foundation.
It taught me how to work hard. It taught
me how to treat people. And it taught me
how to coach the game of football, the
fundamentals, the technique, and it told
me there was no shortcuts. Right? I
wasn't a guy who
all of a sudden started coaching and I
was sitting here in the NFL. I had to
work and I had really good role models
to look to to do that. Um
and I would do it no other way. And what
I take from that
that's how the foundation's going to be
built here.
And it has to be.
And it's got to be built on fundamentals
and technique and it has to be built on
hard work.
And and those are the things that I'm
glad I learned because nothing was easy
for me.
And it's not going to be.
But if you do things right and you're
surround yourself with the right people
and you bring that energy that they had
and pour that love into them like they
did to me,
then look out.
Jeff, I I wanted to ask you about your
experience as a head coach at Boston
College. What did you What did you learn
from that experience and
why did you eventually leave to go back
to the NFL? Yeah, a 40-year-old head
coach who, you know, we just left the
playoffs at Ohio State where I was a
coordinator and
my first week on the job, my first month
on the job, COVID hits.
So, I I had to learn that
everybody's got a plan until you get
punched in the face and I got punched
pretty hard. And what I learned about
myself is you can get through anything
if you get organized, you get detailed,
and you go one step at a time and you
just go to work.
And you surround yourself with the
really good staff
and you pour into your players and you
bring that energy.
Um and I learned a ton. I had to do a
lot there. I had to do academics. I had
to worry about nutrition and residence
halls and everything you can name it and
deal with the board of regents and I had
to be a CEO.
And I'll take a lot with that from there
to me here.
You know, I made mistakes,
right? As a young coach, which you're
going to make in a lot of different ways
and I learned from them
over those 4 years. We had some hard
years. We had some really good years.
But I think those experiences will help
me out a lot as I go forward and I've
grown and I've matured and I have
learned and I can admit those mistakes
and I grow from them
so they won't happen again here.
So, I take a lot with me for those 4
years and I wouldn't trade them. Why did
I leave?
Um at the end of the day, uh
I wanted to coach football.
And there was a lot going on that really
wasn't allowing me to do that anymore.
The landscape had changed with NIL and
the portal and everything else that came
in and when Matt called with an
opportunity, that was really hard for me
to leave. Really hard to leave the staff
and leave the players.
Um but talking to my wife and really
thinking things through,
I want to coach football. It's all I
ever dreamed of. And and I wasn't doing
that anymore and I didn't feel like I
was myself anymore, so we decided it was
what was best. And ultimately, I wanted
to be a head coach again in this league.
So, I bet on myself. I took the job
and now I'm sitting here.
And uh Dave Hyde of the Sun Sentinel. Um
John Eric, you both you guys are
obviously from Green Bay and you bring
that
mindset, the ideas. Could you just talk
and you you you did a little in the
opening of what the Green Bay way is or
what you two hope to bring here.
Sure. I You know, I think in terms of
player acquisition principles and
philosophy, it's you know, I'm I'm being
a little bit redundant, so forgive me if
there's frustration level out there, but
what we've always done is built through
the draft. And again, it's about
culture. Now, we have certain principles
and pillars within how we approach the
draft that I won't get into cuz I don't
want to give away that
you know, the secrets to the sauce, so
to speak. But uh but we're going to
build through the draft. We're going to
retain our own players if at all
possible because of the culture piece of
it. That's I think that has allowed uh
Green Bay to have sustained success over
time. And then again, there's a
financial component, rookie contracts,
all that kind of thing. We will
utilize free agency. We got We have to
get back to a a spot within the salary
cap that'll allow us to do that and we
will. Um
but I think if you look over the years
at the intentionality of which they've
gone about it, you know, Ted was Charles
Woodson.
You know, when Brian Gutekunst first
took the job, we were a little more
active with with how we went about or a
little more active to kind of jump-start
the roster. Za'Darius Smith, who was an
All-Pro that year.
Uh Preston Smith, who finished his Green
Bay tenure with 37 and 1/2 sacks.
Obviously, Josh Jacobs and Xavier
McKinney the years before. So, we're not
we're not just checking boxes so that we
can look busy. We're intentional about
the caliber of player and then what they
bring to the locker room.
You can't have good culture if you got
guys that aren't bought in and wired
right for what you're trying to build.
And so, that's what I would say is we're
going to build through the draft and
we'll be very selective and deliberate
in free agency. I think you have to be.
Uh if you're not, you're you're treading
in dangerous waters. Um but then there's
certain principles within that that
again, I I won't get into cuz I'm
helping out our competition.
Um but I just think the culture and the
caliber of players that we've targeted
over time and then the the
intentionality of the the standard, if
you will, within how we go about our
draft process allows us to uh to to pick
good players, but also hit on players in
the middle and late rounds. I think um
this is not to sit up here and pat
myself on the back or say that Green Bay
is a perfect place. Look, it's not an
exact science. We've missed. You know,
you guys can do your home We've missed.
But we've hit on a lot of players over
my time there in the middle to late
rounds that allow us
to be successful and and and get get
value out of players that maybe some
other teams aren't.
Chris Perkins, South Florida Sun
Sentinel. Uh a question for John Eric.
Um I wanted to know about power
structure, power distribution, whether
you're a strong GM, etc. So, my
questions are what were your role in the
Mike McDaniel firing? What was your role
in the Jeff Hafley hiring? Did you have
final say? Did you have a strong
opinion?
Uh the dominant voice? And what was And
considering that, you know, there's an
outside voice in Troy Aikman outside of
the organization, what was his role in
those in those moves? Yeah, that's a
great question. You know, I'll start
with the the
Mike McDaniel. Um by the time I had
gotten here for my second interview,
Mike Mike had been let go. Uh so, that
was an ownership decision. It was clear
to me in my second
uh interview that we were moving in a
different direction. Um things I'll say
about Mike is we have a lot of mutual
friends in the business, tremendous
amount of respect for him as a football
coach, what he's accomplished, and and
he'll, you know, what he will continue
to accomplish in this league. He's a
brilliant football mind and anybody that
that knows him and knows this game
understands that. But no, I was not
involved in that decision. That had
happened before I got here.
Um
in terms of the power structure with the
hiring of Jeff Hafley,
I came into this and was very
very vocal from the jump that look, I
have a lot of conviction on a guy that
I'm in Green Bay with, but we have to go
into this eyes open. I said it before in
the previous statement, my job is to do
what is best for the Miami Dolphins,
period. No matter how hard or easy it
may be.
And I had to
live by that within the very first
process that I was thrust into. So, yes,
I articulated to Tom and Danny and
Stephen and Troy, Brandon, and Dan how I
felt about him, but I also put together
a list or we put together a list of the
most competitive
potential head coaches out there and I
think we went it We did a great job of
going into it eyes open.
We had great conversations after each
interview. There were a lot of really
strong candidates.
Um and and like like I said, the power
structure is what I am used to in Green
Bay. You know, yes, we don't have an
owner, but essentially Ed Policy is the
owner. In my short time with Stephen and
Danny and Brandon,
it's very clear to me that it he it's
about winning here. It's not about ego
and pride and who has the most stroke.
We It's collaboration with boundaries
and trust. I've said that a thousand
times over again. We all have a role to
play in this. Um and if we don't get in
our own way,
this will be a good thing. Um I have
Brandon has been excellent. We've had in
in 1 week of
of working together, we've had some
great conversations. It's very clear to
me that he is a he's a team player.
Danny's energy is endless. You know, we
talk every day, multiple times a day.
Um Stephen has expressed to me that he's
willing to do anything to win. Tom has
been an excellent resource and Dan and
Troy, I mean,
how do you get better than that? These
guys were two of the best to ever do it
in the history of the game. They have a
a perspective from a player's point of
view. They've had coaches sit out in
front of them and message the team over
and over again. Um
they were phenomenal resources for me as
we went through this. I mean, I would
look at them at the end of it. I'd say,
"You believe in that guy? Would you
follow him?"
If they said yes, it carried weight. How
could it not? Um so, I say all that to
say
the power structure here, I'm very
comfortable with. This is This is never
going to be about me. This is about us
and moving through this thing together
and ultimately winning a lot of football
games, chasing championships. And if we
don't allow ego and pride to get in the
way, we'll be fine.
We've seen other organizations that do
that and then you're running uphill. It
becomes fractured. There's silos and now
you got big problems. We've kind of
vowed to each other on the front end to
not let that happen, and I think it's
all of our responsibilities
to make sure that it doesn't, and I feel
really good about it.
I'm Marcel Louis-Jacques with ESPN. Uh
going to echo everybody else and welcome
you to South Florida. Congrats on the
jobs. Uh question is directed to John
Eric.
Uh what are your thoughts on
Is it John you for Is it John Eric or
>> Yeah, John. You know what? It's a great
question. Let's get this out of the way
now. So, sure, if you want A lot of
people call me J, but most people in my
profession call me Sully. So, you're
you're free to do any of it. I've been
called a lot worse, but most people call
me Sully. All right, Sully. Well, what
are your thoughts on on the Dolphins
quarterback situation? How do you plan
to address that over the coming months?
Sure. I mean, obviously that's a huge
question looming over the organization.
I'd be naive to think that everybody
doesn't understand that. I have a lot of
respect for Tua. He's a good football
player. He's accomplished a lot in this
league. Um
I think
whether it's Tua or anybody else, it's
it's unfair and irresponsible for me to
sit up here and talk about anything
specific before I've talked to the
player himself.
Um quarterback is the most important
position in professional sports. You
know, I also think it's the most
dependent. These guys heard me say this
in the interview process. We will
evaluate that position like we evaluate
every other position, and and we will do
what is best for this football team.
With Tua or anybody else, to sit up here
today and tell you that I have a great
understanding of what we're going to do
or which way we're going to go,
that would be a lie cuz there's just too
much work to do. There's too many
conversations to be had at this point.
Uh a lot of respect for Tua, what he's
accomplished in this league. I thought
Quinn did a great job at the end of the
season.
Um we have to figure that out. We will,
but today is not the day I can give you
that answer. I understand the question.
I just can't give you that answer today.
Uh Will Manso, WPLG-TV Miami. Like
others have said, welcome to South
Florida. Uh
wanted to start with you. It's kind of a
two-part question on the on the search
and the decision. This organization has
gone in the direction of coordinators as
head coaches, first-time head coaches,
for a while now. When you were going
through the process, how much did you
weigh NFL head coaching experience in
that process? How much was that part of
it? And And Jeff, to you as a follow,
just how ready do you think you are to
take that step to be an NFL head coach
in the role, what it takes?
Yeah, sure. I mean, it It It weighed in,
you know. I mean, [clears throat] I
won't talk about specifically who felt
stronger about it than others, but I can
say to you like it was a big deal to me.
I'm a first-time GM. I would be naive to
sit here and think that there aren't
going to be blind spots along the way
that I figure out on the move. I'll
figure them out. We'll be fine, and
we'll do well. I have no doubt about
that. But to have a head coach who sat
in that chair in the National Football
League before would have been a
tremendous asset to me.
Um having said that,
as we went down the road,
it became clear.
I always had the conviction on half.
That doesn't mean that I did I thought a
lot of There were There were really good
conversations that took place. To be
perfectly honest with you, in the last
interview with him,
I sat back and kind of let them lead it
because I thought it was important for
them to ask and get answers to what they
needed to.
It became very clear to me after Half's
Zoom interview that they saw
a lot of what I saw, and that when they
came in and in person, it kind of dotted
the eyes and crossed the Ts and slam
dunked it, if you will. Um I don't know
if I'm answering your question, per se,
but but there was I could watch them
grow in the conviction that I had coming
through the door. But I want to be very
clear,
it was never
done from the start. I know there's a
perception out there. I can appreciate
that. I understand that.
But that is that is a misnomer by a long
shot. There was a process that had to
take place. We all jumped into it with
both feet, eyes open, and we made the We
We made the best decision at the end of
it that we felt like was was going to
take the Miami Dolphins to where they
needed to be.
Yeah.
Okay, you want me to follow up with this
question or you want to I'll follow up
with your question. All right. Um
Yeah, you asked me if I felt ready. The
other thing that I want to reiterate is
you know, I went on a lot of Zooms. I
went on six Zooms. I had six teams call
me right after to try to set up a flight
to go out there.
Um
And And most know those teams just by
reading through it. I chose to come here
first,
and that was very important to me. I
wanted to get a feel
not only for John Eric, but I wanted to
get a feel for Mr. Ross and the entire
organization. And those conversation
led me
to want to be here.
Am I ready?
I kind of took you through my journey,
where I've been, what I've done.
And the head coach experience that I've
had, and then going back and being a
coordinator and running a whole side of
a room, and really being the head coach
of the defense.
I do believe I'm ready.
Now,
are there going to be things that I
learn as we go through this as a
first-time NFL head coach? Yeah.
I mean, that's life.
But what I'm going to do is I'm going to
make sure I surround myself with great
people
and do everything I can that if I do
make those mistakes, that I won't make
them again.
But I feel more than ready,
and more than ready to do it here.
Hi, question for Sully. Um you mentioned
that it's going to be a process of of
building this roster out and and getting
it to where you guys want to be. Just
from a construction standpoint, where
does that start? What area on this
roster does that start with? And
do you realistically need to have a
quarterback in place, have that
situation figured out before you start
to figure other things out, or what's
that process going to look like?
>> Sure. I think you know, obviously the it
always starts with the quarterback. Um
anybody that's in this business will
tell you that, but but we'll you know,
we'll build this from the inside out.
That I think you have to do that. I
think you have to to make sure that your
line of scrimmage on both sides of the
ball
is uh
is big, tough, resilient, and that
there's depth, so that you can survive
the It's a violent game. There's going
to be injuries, that you can survive
injuries. Um the thing that I think we
have to focus most on right now is
making sure that we build
infrastructure. And yes, we need to get
the quarterback situation in place, but
we're not going to do it in an
irresponsible manner, where we sacrifice
building the infrastructure of this
football team, so that when we do find
our guy, he can go be successful. We've
all seen teams that go about it maybe
in a questionable manner, and you get a
really good player at quarterback, but
he can't stay healthy cuz he's getting
killed, or he doesn't have anybody to
throw to. So, we yes,
we will find our guy, but we're going to
make sure that we're building the
infrastructure along the way, so when
when we do find our trigger man, whoever
that may be, whether it's Tua, Quinn, or
somebody that's not in the building, um
we have a team that he can go play with
play and win with.
Good morning. Isaiah Smalls, the Miami
Herald. First question is for Jeff. I
read that you slept in an office for 2
years while at Pitt.
What would you say to that guy now? And
then how did that experience prepare you
for this current moment? And a follow-up
for Sully, what does that humbling
experience say about the guy next to
you?
Yeah.
Um
I did when I when I left um
when I left to go to Pitt, I got dropped
off, and I slept under my desk for 2
years. Um what would I say to that guy
now?
I'd say it worked.
>> [laughter]
>> I mean,
here's why I did it. When I When I left,
I left a full-time job at Albany, where
I coached DBs, and Paul Roads hired me.
Paul, who I have a ton of respect for,
who I later hired at at uh Boston
College. He was a defensive coordinator,
brought me with him to to Pitt.
And what I wanted to do is I wanted to
have no regrets,
and I wanted to give everything that I
had, cuz I had sacrificed a lot. You
know, I
I mean, I really didn't go out. I didn't
do anything but coach football. I missed
family weddings. I missed friends. And I
just said, "I'm going to give everything
I got for 2 years,
and I want to see where this takes me."
And that's what I did. So, I
I woke up real early. I was always the
first one in, and I was always the last
to leave. So, at least I could say no
one could beat me in and out of the
office.
But I gave it everything that I had, so
I'd have no regrets. And then 2 years
later, Coach Wannstedt hired me to be
the secondary coach.
Um
So, I just think it's a It's again, it's
a life lesson of
hard work, and I mean really hard work,
and sacrifice. If you do it,
they pay off.
I think that guy might have been a
little crazier than I am now, but it
worked.
Yeah, to an- to answer the second part
of that question, um not surprising. You
know, I I
I come in or I came into the building in
Green Bay most mornings at at 5:00 a.m.
to to to work out, to to get my day
started, and he he would al- always
be in the building already.
Um so, the work ethic and the passion
for what he does and how he goes about
it, I've seen for 2 years, which is a
big part of what drove me to to you
know, to to the conviction that I had on
him. Um
His work ethic and his desire to win,
and to connect with players, and to do
the little things
when people aren't looking, it's
uncommon.
You know, it's uncommon. Not Not
everybody's willing to do it. And I
think when you're talking about
partnering up with somebody that you can
win with, that's a huge part of it. Like
this guy wants to grind.
He Like the one thing I can say like
we're going to one way, and it's going
to be the hard way. And if you're not
part of it, if you don't want to be part
of it, it doesn't make you a bad human
being, being, but you got to get off the
train.
You know, you're just not It's It's
going to be an uncomfortable environment
for you. And he is not afraid to be
uncomfortable when it comes to work
ethic. Now, he's right though. He He'd
be working out. I I wasn't working out.
>> [laughter]
>> I need to, but he This guy's I mean, he
works out a lot. I'd be like, "Hey
Sully, hey Sully, I got I got work to
do." But I I probably need to start
working out with him soon.
Hey Sully, hey Haf. Welcome. Thank you.
I'm Joe from the Palm Beach Post. Joe
Schad, nice to meet you guys. Nice to
meet you.
Haf, I wanted to ask you about offense
and defense real quick. Uh
do you plan to call defensive plays and
what type of offense would you ideally
have here?
Well, you good questions and thanks for
calling me Haf. It makes me feel very
comfortable though my brother would tell
you he's the first Haf and might get
insulted. Um yeah, I'm going to call
plays.
Uh that's really important to me and I
have a plan in place with
potential hires that will allow me to be
the head coach in the off season kind of
like I watched Kyle Shanahan do it and
kind of like how I watched Matt do it in
Green Bay. But I am going to call plays.
It's really important to me. It's
something that I love to do.
Uh it really connects me with that
group. I think it'll bring a lot of
energy to that side of the football and
I think the details will be exactly how
I want them early on as we go.
Offense and defense, schematic
schematically speaking, it's all going
to start with fundamentals and technique
to me.
Whether that's getting off a block,
whether that's blocking, it's putting
your eyes in the right place, it's
it's the little things that I think are
lost right now in football. So, that
will be the foundation and then what's
it going to look like on offense is what
everybody's going to want to know.
I'm never one to just say, "Here's the
playbook. This is what we're running
regardless of who we have." I'm not like
that.
I want to take a close look at what we
have and I want to make sure we fit that
and give our players the best chance to
succeed. Now, I need to hire an
offensive coordinator. And there's
certain core beliefs that I really do
believe in like running the ball and
being really physical up front. So, when
they know we're going to run the ball,
we're still going to run it well.
That's going to be huge for me. And then
we do, we need to build it around the
quarterback and you have to surround
that quarterback with weapons. The O
line, the wide outs, the backs, so it's
not all him.
Because do I like being under center and
do I like running the football because
the play pass off that, you create
separation between the second and third
level and from a defensive standpoint,
that's really hard. The screen game, the
the keepers, everything looking the
same, hunting explosives, right? Those
are things that have always given me
trouble as a defensive coach
and I'd like to implement some of those,
but it's going to come back to
what can our players do at a high level,
evolve as we go to figure that out to
give them the best chance to have
success and ultimately win. And I've
taken a lot of pride on the defensive
side of the ball, whether we've been 3-4
spacing, 4-3 spacing,
had to evolve this year when Micah
Parsons walked in with a week to go and
had totally had to change stuff.
That's what That's what good coaching
is. It's developing, it's teaching and
it's getting the most out of players.
So, I'm excited for that.
Welcome to the both of you guys. Al
Butler here from UPI. Uh my question's
for Sully.
Um you're coming from a place where it's
pretty rare you had uh on you count on
one hand like the amount of quarterbacks
you had over 30 years. I'm curious what
in that process you learned about
finding that guy and on what you're
going to look for here.
Sure. I mean, I learned uh if you can
help it, don't wait till you don't have
a quarterback to find one. You know what
I mean? That's It starts there. If you
think about what we did with Aaron,
um
you know, I watched Ted Thompson. I I I
referred to him earlier talking about
him always doing what is best for the
team even when it's not popular. You got
to remember Brett was
still in place and playing at a very
high level. Um and there were a lot of
people in that building that didn't
think drafting a quarterback who was
going to sit
for an extended amount of time with a
first round pick made a lot of sense
with where we were as a team.
And he did in that moment what he knew
was best for the Green Bay Packers and
the rest speaks the his you know, the
history speaks for itself. And then and
then we turned around and did it again
with Jordan, you know, we had Aaron. So,
so it starts there, right?
The quarterback position again is the
most important position in in in sports
in my opinion. Certainly the most
important position in football. Um we're
going to invest in that position every
year if we can. Now, depending on where
we are as a football team, it'll be a
different values, but we will draft
quarterbacks every year if not every
other year. Um because I think you have
to, you know, if you hit on a guy, great
and if not, uh if you hit on two, you
have trade value.
Um again, I think if you look at the if
you look at the history of the Green Bay
Packers all the way back to Ron Wolf, I
mean, Brett Favre's backups were
Matt Hasselbeck, Kurt Warner, Aaron
Brooks. You Ty Detmer. You can go on
down the line. Um I can't say enough
about the importance of it and uh and
we'll be very active in in acquiring
quarterbacks uh to make sure that that
room is deep as deep as we can make it.
Did that answer your question okay?
Okay.
All right.
David Furones, South Florida Sun
Sentinel for Haf. What was Monday like
for you? Can you Can you paint the
picture of uh you come in, I'm sure you
have another flight to catch for another
interview and all of a sudden you have a
job offer all while the national
championship is across the street. Yeah,
gosh, that was Monday. That feels like
What a day. I I don't even know what
today is.
Um
One is exciting.
You know, finally get a chance to to fly
in and and have an opportunity to
interview in person for an NFL team.
A little overwhelming. You know, I had
teams while I was in the hotel room
trying to get me on the phone, owners
trying to get me on the phone, Zooms
trying to be set up. I had a team that
was trying to have me leave the hotel
possibly to interview in this state.
Um
But I sat in that hotel. I kept going
over my notes, kept talking to Gina.
Um
and then I went into the interview, you
know, and I did. I had I had a plane
that was waiting to take me somewhere
else. And I sat down with this group
again and and Mr. Ross and Sully and and
we interviewed and they asked more
questions and we talked about staff. And
they, you know, just kind of wanted to
get a better feel and I wanted to do the
same from them.
And then uh be Why not just be totally
honest, right? So, then they told me to
leave the room and I was like, "All
right, I think I got a good chance at
this job." I called my wife and said I I
think I might get it.
And then time went on and it was like 45
minutes went by. I was like, "Maybe I'm
not going to get this. Maybe I need to
get on that plane and call my agent
Trace and say, 'All right, keep that
Keep that plane running. I might be out
of here.'" Then they called me back in
and then they offered me the job. And uh
I think they would probably tell you I
was a little bit overwhelmed and
probably didn't know how to react, but
handshakes and hugs,
immediately asked to call my wife before
the whole world knew about it cuz it was
probably close to getting tweeted out
there. Called my mom, my brother, my
sister and
I just very emotional, very grateful.
And then then to top it off, I get to
sit next to Mr. Ross at the national
championship game. I'm like, "Are you
kidding me?" I mean, could this day get
any better?
Um so, thank you for that question cuz
one of the best days of my life and just
to rehash it with you guys, it's
it was a cool day.
And can I say one thing real quick? I
don't know if this is appropriate or
not, but I'm going to do it. I can I can
now. Um I'm joking. Uh
I want to say,
you know, I came from a place that was
first class in everything they did and
I've been here for a week.
The support staff here,
it's a lot of people who will never get
their names in the paper, but their
willingness and their excellence in
helping me get accustomed and my family,
thank you. It's been amazing and you
guys have made it super easy. So, I just
I I felt like it was necessary to say
that and thank you.
Well said, man.